Register of the Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Dublin, Ireland) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- SERIES NO. 410. TELEGRAMS BETWEEN MINISTRY AND POLAND'S FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS
  - 1944
    - Poland
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
        - September-October
          - German atrocities following Warsaw Uprising (Folder 13: 15)
        - November-December
          - General (Folder 13: 16)
          - Auschwitz. Polish government protest note passed on to Germany through Irish diplomatic channels (Folder 13: 17)
          - Ministry's organizational structure (Folder 13: 18)
          - Polish-British agreement on support for families of deceased soldiers (Folder 13: 19)
          - Transfer of assets captured by the enemy as decided by the the Bretton Woods Conference (Folder 13: 20)
          - Warsaw Uprising according to Polski Komitet Wyzwolenia Narodowego (Folder 13: 21)
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 13: 22)
    - Dublin - Foreign legations (Folder 13: 23)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs
      - General (Folder 13: 24)
      - Protest notes of Polish government
        - Nurnberg trial (Folder 13: 25)
        - Poland's eastern border (Folder 13: 26)
        - Poland's occupation by Soviet forces (Folder 13: 27)
        - Reparation conference in Paris (Folder 13: 28)
    - Poland
      - Consulate, London (Folder 13: 29)
      - Embassy, London (Folder 13: 30)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych) (Box 14)
        - January-February (Folder 14: 1)
        - March-April
          - General (Folder 14: 2)
          - Polish-British mutual assistance agreement, August 25, 1939 (Folder 14: 3)
          - United Nations Conference on International Organization (1945: San Francisco, Calif.) - Polish government position (Folder 14: 4)
        - May-June
          - General
            - General (Folder 14: 5)
            - "Rzad Tymczasowy w Polsce." Government release. (Folder 14: 6)
          - War reparations for Polish citizens (Folder 14: 7)
        - September-October
          - General (Folder 14: 8)
          - Protest note on Soviet occupation of Poland (Folder 14: 9)
        - November-December
          - General (Folder 14: 10)
          - Protest notes
            - Nurnberg trial (Folder 14: 11)
            - Reparation conference in Paris (Folder 14: 12)
  - 1946
    - General
      - January-April (Folder 14: 13)
      - May-August (Folder 14: 14)
      - September-December (Folder 14: 15)
    - Dublin - Foreign diplomatic representations
      - Consulates (Folder 14: 16)
      - Legations (Folder 14: 17)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs
      - General (Folder 14: 18)
      - Protest notes
        - Demobilization of Polish Army in Great Britain (Folder 14: 19)
        - Ratification of Polish-Soviet border (Folder 14: 20)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych
      - January-June (Folder 14: 21)
      - July-December (Folder 14: 22)
  - 1947
    - General (Folder 15: 1)
    - Dublin - Foreign legations (Folder 15: 2)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 15: 3)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych. (Folder 15: 4)
      Includes references to Foreign Minstry's Archives stored in Dublin
  - 1948
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 15: 5)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 15: 6)
  - 1949
    - General (Folder 15: 7)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 15: 8)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych
      - General (Folder 15: 9)
      - Pius XII to Adam Sapieha on tenth anniversary of outbreak of World War II (Folder 15: 10)
  - 1950
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 15: 11)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 15: 12)
  - 1951 (Box 16)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 1)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 2)
  - 1952
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 3)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 4)
  - 1953
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 5)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 6)
  - 1954
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 7)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 8)
  - 1955
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 9)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 10)
  - 1956
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 16: 11)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Folder 16: 12)
  - 1957 (Box 17)
    - General (Folder 17: 1)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 17: 2)
    - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych
      - January-February (Folder 17: 3)
      - March-April (Folder 17: 4)
      - May-June (Folder 17: 5)
      - July (Folder 17: 6)
- SERIES NO. 424/A. DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR NETWORK. POLISH. Recognition of Polish Mission, 1929 (Folder 17: 7)
- SERIES NO. 424/B. DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR NETWORK. FOREIGN, 1929-1931.
  Consulates
  - General (Folder 17: 8)
  - Belgium (Folder 17: 9)
  - Brazil (Folder 17: 10)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 17: 11)
  - France (Folder 17: 12)
  - Germany (Folder 17: 13)
  - Italy (Folder 17: 14)
  - Netherlands (Folder 17: 15)
  - Portugal (Folder 17: 16)
  - Sweden (Folder 17: 17)
- SERIES NO. 429. IDENTIFICATION PAPERS, LAISSEZ-PASSERS, PASSPORTS, FACILITATING OF TRAVEL AND CUSTOMS, 1929-1930 (Folder 17: 18)
- SERIES NO. 439. CIRCULARS
  - 1927-1928 (Folder 17: 19)
  - 1929
    - January-June (Folder 17: 20)
    - July-December (Folder 17: 21)
  - 1930
    - January-April (Folder 17: 22)
    - May-August (Folder 17: 23)
    - September-December (Folder 17: 24)
  - 1931 January-March (Folder 17: 25)
- SERIES NO. 441. BOOK-KEEPING PROTOCOLS (Box 18)
  - 1929 (Folder 18: 1)
  - 1930 (Folder 18: 2)
  - 1931
    - General (Folder 18: 3)
    - Closing operations (Folder 18: 4)
- SERIES NO. 447/A. OFFICE POLICIES. MISSING MAIL, MISDIRECTED MAIL, LOST OR RETURNED MAIL, 1929-1931 (Folder 18: 5)
- SERIES NO. 448. NORMALIZATION OF PAPERWORK, 1930 (Folder 18: 6)
- SERIES NO. 471. SHIFTS OF PERSONNEL. Assignments and nominations, 1929-1930 (Folder 18: 7)
- SERIES NO. 473. VACATIONS, 1929-1931 (Folder 18: 8)
- SERIES NO. 478. VARIOUS PERSONAL MATTERS. Paderewski, Ignacy. Clippings, 1940-1943 (Folder 18: 9)
- SERIES NO. 489. REGISTERS, TERMINOLOGY, 1930-1931 (Folder 18: 10)
- SERIES NO. 497/A. CENTRAL LIBRARY. ORDERING AND PURCHASE OF BOOKS, 1929-1930 (Folder 18: 11)
- SERIES NO. 497/C. CENTRAL LIBRARY. MAILING BOOKS TO FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS, 1929-1931 (Folder 18: 12)
- SERIES NO. 497/D. CENTRAL LIBRARY. REFERENCE LIBRARY, 1930 (Folder 18: 13)
- SERIES 516. COURIER MAIL. Receipts, 1930-1945 (Folder 18: 14)
- SERIES NO. 529. VARIOUS PAYMENTS (RENT, ELECTRICITY, WATER)
  - 1945 (Folder 18: 15)
  - 1946 (Folder 18: 16)
  - 1947 (Folder 18: 17)
- SERIES NO. 530. INVENTORY
  - 1929 (Folder 18: 18)
  - 1930 (Folder 18: 19)
  - 1931 (Folder 18: 20)
- SERIES NO. 538. PERSONAL EXPENDITURES, INSURANCE, ENTERTAINMENT EXPENSES, 1929-1930
  - General (Folder 18: 21)
  - Zaklad Ubezpieczen Pracownikow Umyslowych (Folder 18: 22)
- SERIES NO. 539. WORK RELATED TRIPS, COURIER TRIPS, ENTERTAINMENT EXPENSES, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- SERIES NO. 541. OFFICES, REPRESENTATIONAL OFFICES, AND THEIR INSURANCES
  - 1931 (Folder 19: 2)
  - 1945-1952 (Folder 19: 3)
  - 1953-1957 (Folder 19: 4)
- SERIES NO. 545. SCHOLARSHIPS AND COURSES. Polish Students Fund, 1947-1950
  - General (Folder 19: 5)
  - Circulars (Folder 19: 6)
  - Correspondence (Folder 19: 7)
  - List (Folder 19: 8)
  - Reports (Folder 19: 9)
- SERIES NO. 554. ASSIGNATION OF BUDGETARY SUMS TO REPRESENTATIONS ABROAD
  - 1929 (Folder 19: 10)
  - 1930 (Folder 19: 11)
- SERIES NO. 559. OPENING OF CREDITS. Pre-war credits, 1930 (Folder 19: 12)
- SERIES NO. 560. ISSUES RELATED TO BUDGET AND ACCOUNTING. Bank of Ireland
  - 1929 (Folder 19: 13)
  - 1930 (Folder 19: 14)
  - 1931-1932 (Folder 19: 15)
- SERIES NO. 564. RECEIPTS (Box 20)
  - 1929
    - Accounting reports (Folder 20: 1)
    - Audit documentation (Folder 20: 2)
    - Petty accounts (Folder 20: 3)
    - Staff expenses documentation (Folder 20: 4)
  - 1930
    - Accounting reports (Folder 20: 5)
    - Audit documentation (Folder 20: 6)
    - Petty accounts (Folder 20: 7)
    - Staff expenses documentation (Folder 20: 8)
  - 1931
    - Accounting report (Folder 20: 9)
    - Audit documentation (Folder 20: 10)
    - Petty accounts (Folder 20: 11)
- SERIES NO. 673. CONSULAR INSTRUCTIONS, 1950 (Folder 20: 12)
- SERIES NO. 700. TRANSLATIONS
  - 1943-1948. (Folder 20: 13)
    Includes instructions on Polish citizenship
  - 1944 (Folder 20: 14)
  - 1953-1957 (Folder 20: 15)
- SERIES NO. 701. NOTARY FUNCTIONS, 1930 (Folder 20: 16)
- SERIES NO. 727. PASSPORT ISSUES. FUNDAMENTAL ISSUES
  - 1929-1931 (Folder 20: 17)
  - 1942 (Folder 20: 18)
  - 1943 (Folder 20: 19)
  - 1944
    - General (Folder 20: 20)
    - Philipson Family, Case of (Folder 20: 21)
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 20: 22)
    - Inquiries about emigration to Ireland (Folder 20: 23)
  - 1946 (Folder 20: 24)
  - 1947 (Folder 20: 25)
  - 1948 (Folder 20: 26)
  - 1952-1957. (Folder 20: 27)
    Includes material on possibilities of settlement of Poles in Ireland
- SERIES NO. 729. ISSUANCE AND EXTENSION OF PASSPORTS (Box 21)
  - General. Rejestr Paszportow
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 21: 1)
    - 1946 (Folder 21: 2)
  - 1930-1939 - Invalidation of citizenship - Honig, Teodor (Theodor Hoenig) also known as Moszel (Theodor Moschel) (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - 1945 (Folder 22: 2)
  - 1946 (Folder 22: 3)
  - 1947 (Folder 22: 4)
  - 1948 (Folder 22: 5)
  - 1949 (Folder 22: 6)
  - 1950 (Folder 22: 7)
  - 1951 (Folder 22: 8)
  - 1952 (Folder 22: 9)
  - 1953 (Folder 22: 10)
- SERIES NO. 729/A. ISSUANCE AND EXTENSION OF PASSPORTS. REGULAR PASSPORTS. Polish Jews, 1929-1930 and 1940. (Folder 22: 11)
  Includes original passports
- SERIES NO. 733. VISA REGULATIONS, 1929-1931 (Folder 22: 12)
- SERIES NO. 734. ENTRY AND STAY OF FOREIGNERS IN POLAND. Equestrian competitions, 1930-1931 (Folder 22: 13)
- SERIES NO. 735. POLISH VISAS. Requests for lists of visas issued (Folder 22: 14)
- SERIES NO. 745. MILITARY ISSUES. FUNDAMENTAL ISSUES. Conscripts and internees, servicemen (Folder 22: 15)
- SERIES NO. 746. MILITARY REGULATIONS
  - 1925 - Compulsory military service. (Folder 22: 16)
    Instrukcja dla Urzedow Konsularnych Rz. P. Zagranica o Wykonywaniu Ustawy o Powszechnym Obowiazku Sluzby Wojskowej z Dnia 23 V 1924: Ogolny Skorowidz Rzeczowy
  - 1926 - Okolnik w Sprawie Uzupelnienia I Sprostowania Instrukcji Wojskowej (Folder 22: 17)
- SERIES NO. 755. POLISH ARMY ABROAD.
  - Bevin, Ernest, letter from Rada Polskich Stronnictw Politycznych on demobilization of Polish Army, April 9, 1946 (Folder 22: 18)
  - Stowarzyszenie Polskich Kombatantow, 1952-1956 (Folder 22: 19)
- SERIES NO. 761. INFORMATION RELATED TO NATIONAL SECURITY. Communist separatists, 1930 (Folder 22: 20)
- SERIES NO. 761/E. BYELORUSSIAN MOVEMENT
  - 1941 (Folder 22: 21)
  - 1942 (Folder 22: 22)
- SERIES NO. 761/G. UKRAINIAN MOVEMENT.
  - 1940 (Folder 22: 23)
  - 1941 (Folder 22: 24)
  - 1942 (Folder 22: 25)
  - 1943 (Folder 22: 26)
- SERIES NO. 767. REPORTS FROM SHIPS. Registration forms, 1930-1931 (Folder 22: 27)
- SERIES NO. 773. INFORMATION ON TRADE (Box 23)
  - 1931 - Tomaszow Silk Company (Folder 23: 1)
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 23: 2)
    - Polish Association for Foreign Trade (Folder 23: 3)
  - 1946 (Folder 23: 4)
  - 1947 (Folder 23: 5)
  - 1952-1957 (Folder 23: 6)
- SERIES NO. 788. LOANS AND RELIEF
  - 1943. (Folder 23: 7)
    Includes cases of financial aid to Stanislaw Dunin - Markiewicz and Stanislaw Pobudkiewicz
  - 1944 (Folder 23: 8)
  - 1945 - Parcels (Folder 23: 9)
  - 1948 (Folder 23: 10)
- SERIES NO. 790. POLSKI CZERWONY KRZYZ (POLISH RED CROSS)
  - 1940 (Folder 23: 11)
  - 1943 (Folder 23: 12)
  - 1944 (Folder 23: 13)
  - 1945 (Folder 23: 14)
- SERIES NO. 790/A. INTERNATIONAL RED CROSS. Irish Red Cross
  - 1941 (Folder 23: 15)
  - 1943 (Folder 23: 16)
  - 1944 (Folder 23: 17)
  - 1945-1947 (Folder 23: 18)
  - 1953-1956 (Folder 23: 19)
- SERIES NO. 791. DONATIONS AND COLLECTIONS FOR VARIOUS CAUSES. Parcels to Poland
  - 1948 (Folder 23: 20)
  - 1949 (Folder 23: 21)
  - 1950 (Folder 23: 22)
- SERIES NO. 801. INDIVIDUALS SEARCHED FOR AND ATTAINMENT OF ADDRESS
  - 1930. (Folder 23: 23)
    Includes papers of Maria Lamek and James Berry
  - 1945-1946 (Folder 23: 24)
  - 1949-1956 (Folder 23: 25)
- SERIES NO. 806/D. ART AND LITERATURE. Krzyzanowski, Konrad, 1930-1931 (Folder 23: 26)
- SERIES NO. 819. MINISTERSTWO SKARBU (MINISTRY OF FINANCE). FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS, TRANSFERS, FUNDING OF SECRET AND OFFICIAL GOVERNMENT OPERATIONS DURING WARTIME. Skarb Narodowy
  - 1949 (Folder 23: 27)
  - 1950 (Folder 23: 28)
  - 1951 (Folder 23: 29)
  - 1952 (Folder 23: 30)
  - 1953 (Folder 24: 1)
  - 1954
    - Correspondence (Folder 24: 2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 24: 3)
  - 1955 (Folder 24: 4)
- SERIES NO. 826. PREMIER. Sikorski, Wladyslaw. Letters of condolences upon his death, 1943 July (Folder 24: 5)
- SERIES NO. 838. DZIENNIK USTAW
  - 1953 (Folder 24: 6)
  - 1954 (Folder 24: 7)
  - 1955 (Folder 24: 8)
  - 1956 (Folder 24: 9)
  - 1957 (Folder 24: 10)
- SERIES NO. 865. REVISION OF BORDERS
  - 1941-1942. (Folder 24: 11)
  - 1943
    - Clippings (Folder 24: 12)
    - Reports
      - Groupement Interallie pour l'etude des activites des Allemands et de leurs satellites, nos. 69-87 (Folder 24: 13)
      - Ministerstwo Spraw Kongresowych
        - The Problem of Plebiscites (Folder 24: 14)
        - The Problem of Prussia. Slask Opolski (Folder 24: 15)
        - Tezy w Sprawie Ukladu Wstepnego Dotyczacego Stosunku z Niemcami po Ukonczeniu Dzialan Wojennych (Folder 24: 16)
        - The Transfer of Germans from Poland (Folder 24: 17)
        - Zajscia w Lubelskim a Niemiecka Polityka Narodowa w Generalnym Gubernatorstwie (Folder 24: 18)
  - 1953 - Adenauer: Nigdy Odra-Nysa, by Stanislaw Stronski (Folder 24: 19)
  - 1954
    - Linia Odry i Nysy w Polityce Zachodu, by Dr. Z. Jordan (Folder 24: 20)
    - Przylaczenie Ziem Zachodnich do Polski: Podstawy Stanowiska Polskiego, by Dr. M. Grazynski (Folder 24: 21)
    - Stanowisko Polskie w Sprawie Granicy na Odrze I Nysie Luzyckiej a koncepcje Niemieckie, by Dr. M. Grazynski (Folder 24: 22)
- SERIES NO. 904. ORGANIZATION, PERSONNEL, BUDGET, ACCOUNTING, FINANCES OF POLISH DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR REPRESENTATIONS. Consulate General in Dublin
  - Budget file
    - 1931 (Folder 24: 23)
    - 1945. (Folder 24: 24)
      Includes telegram from Adam Pragier concerning dissolution of government's central offices
    - 1946 (Folder 24: 25)
    - 1948 (Folder 24: 26)
    - 1950 (Folder 24: 27)
    - 1951 (Folder 24: 28)
  - Individual files, 1929-1931 (Folder 24: 29)
  - Inventory, 1929-1945 (Folder 25: 1)
  - Ledgers (Box 26)
    - 1931 May-July; 1942 September - 1944 December (Folder 26: 1)
    - 1945 January-June; 1952 March - 1956 December; 1957 January and May-July (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - 1945 July - 1952 February (Folder 27: 2)